Doctor! Up here!
博士，上这儿来！
Thank you very much, Miss Smith. A most timely rescue.
非常感谢你，史密斯小姐，救援来得正是时候
This isn't a rescue, Doctor, it's a capture.
这不是救援，博士，这是抓捕
Let's get him out of here.
我们先带他离开这里
That fellow has the gall of a camel and the cunning of a fox!
那个家伙有着骆驼的胆汁，狐狸的狡猾!
You shall have your revenge, Captain.
He'll be with Sir Edward now.
你得要报这个仇，头儿，他现在去了爱德华爵士那里了
And not even a rat will come out of that castle alive tomorrow.
到了明天，就是一只耗子也别想活着从那个城堡里出来
By the stars, Bloodaxe, I swear I'll chop him up so fine
对着星星发誓，Bloodaxe，我会把他切碎
not even a sparrow will fill its beak at one peck!
碎得连麻雀都没法下嘴
One of my workers has disappeared.
我的一个工人不见了
Order a search of your castle.
下令搜索你的城堡吧
If you've lost one of your dumb, whey-faced ninnies, Linx,
如果你那些面色惨白的蠢人少了一个，Linx
then look for him yourself. My men are at rest.
你得自己去找。我的人正在休息
We march on Sir Edward within the hour.
我们一个小时内就要向爱德华爵士进军
I insist upon a search, Irongron.
The Doctor is of great value to me.
我坚持要求搜索，Irongron。博士对我价值非凡
And while he is at large, he could be dangerous.
而且如果他逍遥在外的话，就无比危险
The Doctor?
博士？
Bother me now, little toad,
and you will feel an axe in your skull!
这会儿烦我的话，小蟾蜍，小心我的斧头砍掉你的脑袋！
Master, I heard someone call ''Doctor''
while we were at that fellow's heels.
主人，我们在追那个家伙的时候，听到谁喊了一声“博士”
Is this Doctor a long shank rascal with a mighty nose?
这个博士是不是个长腿的家伙，有个大鼻子？
That is how he would appear in human eyes.
在人类眼中他应该是那样
Then he is no longer here.
那他现在已经不在这里了
Sir Edward sent raiders to my castle,
captured him.
爱德华爵士派了人到我的城堡来，把他抓走了
He has escaped!
他居然逃了！
- Tell Sir Edward we're back.
- Yes.
- 告诉爱德华爵士我们这就回去 - 遵命
- Now...
- You've been getting around, Sarah.
- 现在...  - 你还真是阴魂不散啊，莎拉
Are you on visiting terms with all the local nobility?
你跟这里所有本地贵族都有来往？
Doctor, let's get a few things straight, shall we?
博士，我们有话直说，好吗
Oh, dear. I'm afraid you're going to be awfully confused
哦，亲爱的，我担心你会非常困惑的
if you ask me to explain about the Tardis.
如果你想问我的是 TARDIS 是怎么回事的话
- The Tardis?
- Yes, my police box.
- TARDIS?  - 是的，我的警察电话亭
You were a stowaway, I imagine.
你是个偷渡客，我想
Yes, but we'll come to that later.
是的，但这个问题我们稍后再说
- Now then, why are you helping Irongron?
- My dear girl, I'm not helping him.
- 现在说说，你为什么要帮 Irongron？
- 亲爱的姑娘，我没在帮 Irongron
Linx is. I'm trying to stop him.
Linx才在帮，我一直想阻止他
SARAH: Linx?
Yes, perhaps you're lucky enough not to have met him yet.
是的，也许你是运气太好了，还没有碰到他
Nasty, brutish and short just about sums him up.
用几个词来总结的话，他是个险恶, 野蛮和短小的家伙
There was a strange-looking knight with Irongron.
Irongron 那里是有一个长相奇特的骑士
Yes, he'd have looked even stranger
if he hadn't been wearing space armour.
是的，如果他没有戴太空头盔的话，会看起来更奇怪
He comes from a planet
where the surface gravity is many times that of Earth.
他来的那个星球，重力是地球的好几倍
- A man from the stars?
- Mmm-hmm.
- 一个从星星上来的人？  - 嗯哼
- How do I know you're telling the truth?
- Because I never lie.
- 我怎么知道你说的是实话？ - 因为我从不撒谎
Well, hardly ever.
好吧，基本上从不
You ever heard of UNIT?
你听说过 UNIT 吗？
You work for UNIT?
你为 UNIT 工作？
In an advisory capacity, yes.
是的，以顾问的身份
They asked me to look into this question
of the missing scientists for them.
他们让我帮忙调查一下有科学家失踪的问题
But I thought you were responsible for that.
但我觉得你才是这事的黑手
My dear girl, I don't go round kidnapping scientists!
亲爱的姑娘，我不会去绑架科学家！
No, Linx brought them here to staff his workshop.
不，Linx 把他们带到这里来了，用作他工作间的工人
Now I've got to find a way of
sending them back to their own time.
现在我得找到一个方法，把他们送回自己的时间去
- This is the magician?
- Yes. This is the Doctor.
- 这位就是那个魔法师？ - 是的，他是博士
You have done well, Sarah.
你做得很好，莎拉
How do you do?
你好
It is a pleasure and a privilege
to be in the company of civilised people at last.
我很高兴，也很荣幸，终于见到文明人了
A courtly rogue.
这家伙还挺有礼貌
Is he willing to change his allegiance
and serve Sir Edward instead of Irongron?
他愿意改变效忠对象，从 Irongron 转向为爱德华爵士服务吗？
Well, he says he wasn't serving Irongron.
哦，他说他没在为 Irongron 服务
And there is another stranger at the castle,
someone called Linx.
在那个城堡里还有另外一个陌生人，叫 Linx
Yes, he's your enemy, I assure you,
not me.
是的，他才是你的敌人，我不是，我向你保证
We'd be well advised to join forces against him.
我倒非常建议我们连起手来对付他
- Does he speak truth?
- I'm not sure.
- 他说的是实情吗？  - 我不太确定
I suppose I could have been wrong.
我想我可能是搞错了
That's a generous admission.
那还算坦诚
Especially coming from one of the fair sex.
尤其是这话来自一位公平的性别(?)
Or he could just be changing sides to save his own skin.
也或者他是临阵倒戈，只是为了自己的小命
These wizards and warlocks were ever a treacherous breed.
巫师和术士从来都是奸诈的家伙
We'd best be wary of him.
我们最好小心他
I shall spare your life
我打算饶了你的命
if you cast your spells and incantations
to help me against Irongron, Doctor.
前提是你要帮我，用魔法与咒语对付 Irongron，博士
Refuse and you die.
如果拒绝你就死了
You offer a somewhat restricted choice, Sir Edward.
你给我的选择很有限啊，爱德华爵士
EDWARD: What is your answer?
你的答案是什么？
My services are at your disposal, sir.
我听候您的差遣，爵士
- Such as they are.
- Good.
- 跟他们一样  - 很好
Serve me straight, Doctor, and I shall reward you well.
为我服务，博士，我将给你很好的回报
Oh, master... Oh, but, master,
Irongron marches here before noon!
噢，主人...但是，主人，Irongron 的队伍午前就能到达这里！
We heard this said from his own mouth.
我们听到他亲口说的
Then we are lost. We cannot stand against them.
那我们就完了，我们没法跟他们对抗
- On the contrary, sir, I think we can.
- But how? With a handful of men?
- 恰恰相反，爵士，我觉得我们可以 - 怎么对抗？就这几个人？
Yes, sir, with just a few men I think
I can persuade Irongron that we have a full garrison.
是的，爵士，虽然只有几个人，我想我能让 Irongron 认为我们驻扎了大批人马
By the use of your magic?
凭着你的魔法？
By creating an illusion, anyway.
制造一个假象就行
Your magic will have to be powerful
indeed to discourage Irongron.
你的魔法必须的足够强大才能吓退 Irongron
It will be, sir.
会的，爵士
- The men are ready, Captain.
- Good.
- 人都就绪了，头儿   - 很好
Though for such an easy conquest as this,
即便是一趟如此容易的任务
'tis scarce worth strapping on armour!
穿戴上盔甲还是值得的
You and I alone, good Bloodaxe, could take that castle!
我的好 Bloodaxe，你跟我两个人，就可以拿下这座城堡！
Indeed we could, Captain.
我们还真可以，头儿
With Sir Edward's treasure I shall hire more men,
夺了爱德华爵士的财宝，我又可以招募更多人手了
and with Linx's weapons to arm them,
who shall stand against us?
再配备上 Linx 制造的武器，谁还敢跟我们做对？
When does the fighting start, Irongron?
战斗什么时候开始，Irongron?
In the time it takes to ride from here to Sir Edward's castle.
我们从这里出发去爱德华爵士的城堡，一到就开打
- Then I shall come with you.
- What, you?
- 那我跟你一起去   - 什么，你？
Ha! Bloodaxe, on my oath,
can you see that on a scaling ladder?
哈！Bloodaxe, 我得发誓，你可能看见这家伙站在攻城梯上面吗？
I have an interest in seeing the battle.
我有兴趣观看战斗过程
Those eyes have a thirst for blood.
那双眼睛很渴望见血啊
Well, find our bold warrior a horse, Bloodaxe.
好，给我们勇敢的战士找一匹马，Bloodaxe
Come, then!
那就来吧！
- Here's a few more for you, Doctor.
- Thank you, Sarah.
- 这里还给你找了一些，博士  - 谢谢你，莎拉
Lady Eleanor's got every serving wench
in the castle sewing away like mad.
Eleanor 夫人让城堡里面的所有侍女都在做缝制，跟疯了似的
I told you there'd be plenty of work
for everybody, didn't I?
我跟你说过每个人都有很多工作要做，对不？
Oh. Typically masculine arrangement, though.
噢，这安排就是典型的大男子主义
We do all the dirty work, you get all the fun.
所有脏活累活都我们干，你就乐趣独享
You don't think mixing this singularly noxious compound is fun, do you?
你不会认为搅拌这些罕见的有毒化合物是一种乐趣吧，是吗？
- How's the rest of it going?
- Not bad.
- 其它事情怎么样了？  - 不赖
I put Sir Edward in charge of painting the dummies' faces.
我让爱德华爵士负责画这些假人的脸
He's turned out to be quite an artist.
结果发现他还是个不错的艺术家
- Once I'd set him on the right lines.
- Excellent.
- 看来我还给他安排对了 - 非常好
- I'm glad I decided to let you stay.
- You decided?
- 我很高兴我当时决定让你留下来了 - 你决定的？
You know, I was never much of a hand
with a paint brush myself.
你知道吗，我几乎从来没有自己拿过画笔
- No?
- No.
- 没有？  - 没有
Nor a palette knife for that matter.
也没有拿过调色板刀
I'd like to study under one of the masters one day.
我想有一天我要到其中一个大师那里去学习去
Rembrandt, preferably.
伦勃朗，我比较偏好这个
- Rembrandt!
- Mmm-hmm.
- 伦勃朗！  - 嗯哼
Can you... Can you just go anywhere
you like in that Tardis?
你能...你能去任何你想去的地方吗，就坐你那个 TARDIS ？
Yes, within reason.
是的，只要有合适的理由
Then why are you staying here?
Why don't you go somewhere safer?
那为什么你要呆在这里？ 为什么你不去别的安全些的地方？
Because, my dear Sarah, I've got a job to do.
因为，亲爱的莎拉，我有工作要做
One that involves the whole future of your species.
其中一项跟你们这个物种的整体前途有关
Here, hold this will you?
拿住这里，可以吗？
- My species?
- Mmm-hmm.
- 我们这个物种？  - 嗯哼
You're talking as if you weren't human.
你说得好像你不是人似的
Well, the definition of the word ''humanity''
说起来呢，“人性”这个词的定义
was always rather a complex question, wasn't it?
一直都是一个挺复杂的问题，是吧
You know perfectly well what I mean.
Are you or aren't you?
你完全清楚我是什么意思，是还是不是？
If you mean am I a native of the planet Terra,
如果你问的是我是不是地球这个星球的原住民
the answer is no, I'm not.
答案是不，我不是
- Well, what are you, then?
- Me? I'm a Time Lord.
- 那，你是什么呢？  - 我？我是个时间领主
- A Time Lord?
- Yes, that's right.
- 一个时间领主？  - 是的，正是
And my people are very keen
to stamp out unlicensed time travel.
我的人民非常热衷于消灭未授权的时间旅行
You can look upon them as
galactic ticket inspectors if you like.
你可以把他们看作星际的检票员
- Galactic ticket inspectors?
- Mmm-hmm.
- 星际检票员？  - 嗯哼
I could murder a cup of tea. You're serious, aren't you?
我真想喝杯茶。你是说真的，是吗？
About what I do, yes. Not necessarily the way I do it.
对于我做什么，是真的。对于我做事的方法，则不一定
That's made them stop and think, anyway.
不管怎样，这使得他们停下来考虑考虑了
They've got guns!
他们有枪！
No man has fallen, Captain!
没有人掉下来，头儿！
- Your weapons do not work, Linx!
- You do not shoot them straight!
- 你的武器不管用，Linx  - 你都射偏了
Watch.
看着
- LINX: Those figures are dummies.
- Bah, your weapons are useless!
- 那些是假人
- 呸，你的武器一点用也没有
They do not move nor fall. They are not living men.
他们没移动也没掉下来，肯定不是活人
IRONGRON: I smell that fox of a Doctor behind this.
我闻到了博士那个狐狸的味道
Bring up the scaling ladders!
把攻城梯扛上来！
Here they come, Doctor!
他们攻来了，博士
(MEN YELLING)
Away! Away!
撤退！撤退！
Come on, move it!
快点，动起来
What was that stuff, Doctor? Some kind of gas?
那个是什么东西，博士？某种毒气吗？
Gas?
毒气？
Good heavens, what on earth do you take me for?
天啊，你把我当作什么人了？
No, it was some sort of superior stink bomb
不是，只是一种超级臭弹
with a few bangs and flashes thrown in for good measure.
混进去了一点儿能产生声音和闪光的东西
It's quite harmless, I assure you, but...
是相当无害的，我向你保证，不过...
(SNIFFING)
(MEN COUGHING)
Bring me wine! Wine, I say!
拿酒来！酒，我说了！
To quench the dust from my throat
and the stench from my nostrils.
冲冲我喉咙里的灰尘和鼻孔里的臭味
More, wench, more!
再来，丫头，再来！
Am I a sparrow to quench my thirst
with a few scant drops?
当我是只麻雀吗, 就几滴够解渴吗？
Ooh, mice!
噢，鼠辈！
A few loud noises, a few bad smells
and you scatter like sheep!
一点点响声，一点点臭味，你们就跟羊群一样逃散了！
It was sorcery, master.
那是魔法，主人
Black devil's work. You said so yourself.
黑魔鬼干的，你自己都说过
This wizard, the Doctor, he's gone and joined Sir Edward,
那个巫师，叫博士的那个，逃走后加入了爱德华爵士那边
and he threw all the fires and the stenches of hell itself at us!
是他朝我们扔那些冒烟冒恶臭的东西
With poltroons like these,
就你们这群懦夫，
it were ill work to lay siege to a hen coop!
就算围攻鸡舍都会一败涂地
They do but need food and rest to recover their spirits, Captain.
他们只是需要一些食物和休息，马上就能恢复士气了，头儿
We attack again tomorrow morning.
我们明早再次发起攻击
I will take Sir Edward's castle
我要拿下爱德华爵士的城堡
or I will see every man of you perish in the attempt!
要不然我要看到你们一个个都在攻城中战死
Chicken-hearted knaves!
胆小的鼠辈！
Begone from my sight!
从我面前消失！
Did I not see you yourself leading their retreat, Captain?
不是你带领他们撤退的吗，难道是我看错了，队长？
Taunt me not, little toad face.
不要奚落我，小蟾蜍脸
Or by the stars I'll see if the colour
of your blood is red like mortal man's.
要不然群星在上，我要看看你的血是不是跟凡人一样也是红的
You Earth creatures give up too easily.
你们地球生物太容易放弃了
I doubt if you have the potential
to make a truly military species.
我怀疑你们是不是有这个潜力，成为一个真正的军事种族
And you, Linx, you claim to like war.
还有你，Linx，你宣称你喜欢战争
- I haven't seen you doing much this day.
- I came only to observe.
- 今天我可没见你有什么作为  - 我去只是为了观察
I should have known better than
to look for interest in a struggle of primitives
我早应该知道, 不应该在原始人的斗争中寻找乐趣
Threaten me once more and I will destroy you.
再敢威胁我一次，我就毁了你
Why, you...
为什么，你...
Primitives! Childish, squabbling primitives!
原始人！孩子气, 只会哇哇乱叫的原始人!
It is well I do not need to spend much more time among you.
我不需要跟你们这里耗太多时间，那真是太好了
(ALL LAUGHING)
EDWARD: More wine, Doctor?
再来点酒吗，博士？
No, thank you, no. Oh, well, just perhaps a little.
不要了，谢谢，不了。噢，好吧，也许可以再来一点
Those knaves of Irongron's, they ran like rabbits!
Irongron 的那些混混，跑得跟兔子一样
Finest sight that ever I saw, Doctor.
And all thanks to you and your wizardry.
我见过的最漂亮的场景，博士。这都得感谢你和你的魔法
Well, we all played our part, Sir Edward.
哦，是大家群策群力，爱德华爵士
Now your magic works for us, our troubles are over.
现在有你的魔法为我们服务，我们的问题就结束了
No, not quite, I'm afraid.
不，还没完全结束，恐怕
The Doctor thinks Irongron's bound to attack again.
博士觉得 Irongron 还会再次攻击
And you shall affright the knaves with more of your sorceries.
那你再来几个魔法，把那些混混都吓退
It won't work indefinitely, I fear.
它不会一直有效，我担心
This time we had the element of surprise.
这次我们攻其不备
They won't be frightened off quite so easily again.
他们不会再那么容易被吓跑了
Then we've gained a respite. No more.
那我们赢得了一点喘息的机会。没别的了？
Actually, the Doctor does have another idea.
事实上，博士有另外一个主意
Then let us hear your counsel, Doctor.
So far you have served us well.
那我们来听听你的计策，博士。到目前为止，你为我们服务得很好
Well, there's one sure way to prevent Irongron
from capturing your castle.
有一个方法可以阻止 Irongron 夺取你的城堡
And that is?
这个方法是...？
You must capture his.
你必须夺取他的
(SCOFFS)
You advise the impossible, Doctor.
They outnumber us so greatly.
你的建议不现实，博士，他们人数远超过我们
My lady, are you familiar with these herbs and simples?
夫人，你熟悉这些草药和原料吗？
Ragwort, henbane, love-in-a-mist, fennel, sesame.
狗舌草, 天仙子, 黑种草, 茴香, 芝麻
Most we have dried in the kitchens.
The rest grow in the woods nearby.
大多数我们厨房里面有晒干的，其余的都生长在附近的树林里
Excellent. I want to brew up a little draught.
很好，我想酿造一点草药
You mean to mix a magic potion to slay the dog?
你的意思是混合一种神奇的药水来杀狗？
No, not quite. Just something
to calm him down a little.
不，不是那样。只是让他平静一点
I should have slain the filthy little toad there and then.
我应该当时就宰了那头肮脏的蟾蜍
I should have carved him up
into callops on the spot.
我应该当场打得他哭爹喊娘
Aye, master, it puzzles me
as to why you did not.
是啊，主人，我还奇怪为什么你没动手
Aye, well 'tis a matter of high policy, do you see?
这个，是个高级策略的问题，明白吗？
Above your understanding, hmm?
不是你能理解的，嗯？
As yet, we still need Linx's aid.
目前而言，我们还需要 Linx 的协助
Weapons he has promised me and by the stars,
weapons I shall have.
他答应给我的武器，星星在上，我要得到那些武器
Wonderful, magical weapons,
很不错的魔法武器
that will crumble the castles of those that oppose me into dust.
能把我对手的城堡轰成渣
And then, and only then,
shall Linx die by my hand!
到那时，也只有在那时，Linx 会死在我手上
Oh, 'tis a cunning plan, Captain.
哦, 这是一个狡猾的计划, 头儿
Aye, 'tis as well for you dolts that you have me to guide you.
是的, 有我来领导你们, 这对你们来说真是好啊
(CHUCKLES)
There's more to war than hard strokes, my good Bloodaxe.
除了硬碰硬，战争还有很多东西呢，我的好 Bloodaxe
Aye, master.
是，主人
Yours is indeed a towering intelligence.
你的智慧确实是高
Hold, Friar. What business have you here?
停下，修士，你们来这里干什么？
We come to beg alms of the good Captain Irongron.
我们来找 Irongron 队长请求一点施舍
The fame of his charity is spread far and wide.
他的慈善名声广为流传
You will find Captain Irongron in the great hall.
你可以在大厅找到 Irongron 队长
He is indeed a kindly and charitable man
他确实是个善良仁慈的人
and his temper is most sweet and pleasant.
而且他的脾气也很温和，令人愉快
Pass, Friar.
过去吧，修士
Heaven will reward you, my son. Come, brother.
老天会报答你们的，我的孩子。来吧，兄弟
(CHUCKLES)
'Tis to be hoped the two friars are fleet of foot,
看着吧，要么这两个修士就得仓皇逃走
or the church will have two new martyrs ere long.
要么教堂就得多两个殉道者了
(DOOR RATTLING)
What's that?
那是什么
That's a Sontaran spaceship, to be precise,
那是桑塔人的宇宙飞船，确切地说
and tremendously powerful for its size,
just like its owner.
从尺寸来看它非常强大，就跟他的主人一样
Here, give me your habit.
来，把你的外套给我
- What's wrong with him?
- Deep hypnosis.
- 他怎么了？ - 深度催眠
Ah, there you are, Doctor! Back again, eh?
啊，你在这儿啊，博士！又回来了？
- SARAH: Professor Rubeish!
- What?
- Rubeish 教授！  - 什么？
Oh, it's you!
哦，是你！
Doctor, I knew this girl was involved.
We should have reported her as I wanted.
博士，我知道这个女孩有份参与，我的意见是我们应该举报她
Yes, well, I'm very glad we didn't.
是的，不过我很高兴我们没有
In a few hours, that ship's going to be ready for takeoff.
再过几个小时，那艘飞船就可以起飞了
Yes, he's been working these people at a killing pace.
Come over here.
是的, 他一直在往死了用这些人。快过来这儿
Look.
看
No sleep. Practically no food.
They're starting to collapse like flies.
没有觉睡，基本没有食物。他们的身体开始崩溃了
I'm not surprised. He's suffering from near starvation.
我不觉得奇怪，他几乎要饿死了
We'll have to get them some food, Doctor,
or at least a drink.
我们必须得给他们找点食物，博士，至少得找点喝的
- There's no time for that.
- They'll die if we don't.
- 没时间干那个了 - 我们不管的话他们要死了
Sarah, listen to me.
莎拉，听我说
Linx's spaceship is just about ready for takeoff.
Linx 的飞船很快就要可以起飞了
And when that happens, there's going
to be the most tremendous explosion.
到那个时候，将会发生最强烈的爆炸
Everybody in this castle will die.
这个城堡里面的所有人都会死
These are the weapons I have promised you.
这些是我许诺给你的武器
Also a good supply of the projectiles that they use.
还有它们所需要的弹丸，很充足了
Oh, my thanks, good toad face... Good Linx.
噢，感谢，我的好蟾蜍脸...好 Linx
More weapons from the stars.
来自星星的更多武器
I shall complete the repairs of the improved fighting robot
那个改进过的战斗机器人，我会完成对它的修理
if I have time before I leave.
如果我离开之前还有时间的话
If you wish to leave, then you would do well to obey me.
如果你想要离开，那你最好服从我
Do you threaten me?
你是在威胁我？
I leave when I am ready, and that will be soon.
我准备好了就离开，很快了
And will you carry your starship on your back, good toad?
那你会把你的飞船背在后背吗，好蟾蜍？
You needed my knaves to bring it here,
you will need them to take it hence.
你需要我的喽罗把它拖过来，你也需要他们把它弄出去
Evidently you have no understanding
显然你并不了解
of the forces involved in interstellar travel.
星际旅行需要什么动力
I shall leave when I am ready.
我准备好了就会离开
It would be foolish of you to attempt to stop me.
你们试图阻止我的话，那就太蠢了
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士，你在干什么？
- Trying to break this hypnosis.
- It's very deep.
- 试着破解对他的催眠  - 程度很深
Narcoleptic condition, eh?
嗜睡症状，嗯？
The brain can still receive signals, Professor.
他大脑还可以接收信号，教授
Why can't you just send them as they are?
为什么不现在这样子送他们回去？
It's too risky with their minds in this state.
以他们的意识目前的状态来说，这样风险太大了
The transition might damage them permanently.
迁移过程可能会对他们造成永久损伤
I've never heard so much gobbledegook in me life.
我这辈子从来没听说过这样晦涩难懂的句子
But I expect you know what you're talking about.
但我还指望你能知道你在说什么
- Polka time!
- BOTH: What?
- 好戏来了！ - 什么？
It's the beat. Look, he's beginning to respond.
是节拍，看，他开始有回应了
Hide!
躲起来！
Up!
起来！
Get back to work!
回去工作！
Work! What's wrong with you?
工作！你怎么回事？
Get up or I will kill you!
起来，否则我杀了你！
- Leave him, Linx!
- Ah!
- 放开他，Linx！ - 啊！
How fortunate that you have returned, Doctor.
这么幸运，你回来啦，博士
My failure to destroy you
我没能干掉你
was the one thing that marred the pleasure
这件事让我很扫兴
of my approaching departure from this miserable planet.
眼看我就要离开这个悲惨的星球了
Don't you want to know why I've returned?
你不知道为什么我会回来吗？
It is of no interest to me.
我对这个没有兴趣
I came here to offer you my help.
我来这里是提供帮助的
We're sworn enemies, Doctor. Why should you help me?
我们是死敌，博士，为什么要帮我？
Because I want something from you.
因为我需要你提供点东西
If you will let me de-hypnotise people
and send them home
如果你让我解除这些人的催眠，把他们送回家
and help me capture Irongron and his men,
并且帮我抓住 Irongron 和他的人
then I will assist you in the repairs to your spaceship.
那我就帮助你维修飞船
Now, the weapons that you've made for Irongron
现在，你为 Irongron 造的这些武器
you can leave here in the castle.
你可以留在城堡里面
When it's empty, you can take off,
搬空之后，你就可以起飞了
destroying castle and weapons at the same time.
同时将城堡和武器一同销毁
All right, Commander Linx,
怎样，Linx 指挥官
what do you say?
你怎么说？
- You wish for my answer, Doctor?
- I do.
- 你期望我回答吗，博士  - 是的
Then here it is.
这就是了